Guide to the Othniel Charles Marsh Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Red Cloud Agency, 1838-1891; Series VII
  - Walker's report on issues made by Saville during Marsh's visit to Red Cloud, 1874 November (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Saville's returns for provisions, etc. at Red Cloud, Final Quarter, 1874 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Indian Affairs Authorization for Marsh's trip to Red Cloud, 1873 June-July (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Indian Affairs Memos, etc., 1875 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Red Cloud Correspondence, 1875 April-May (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Red Cloud Notes and Correspondence, 1875 June 1-15 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Red Cloud Correspondence, 1875 June 17-30 (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Red Cloud Correspondence, 1875 July 1-6 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Red Cloud Correspondence, 1875 July 7-13 (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Red CIoud Correspondence and Newsclippings, 1875July 14-18 (Box 52, Folder 16)
  - Red Cloud Corresnondence and Newsclipping, 1875 July 19-21 (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Red Cloud Correspondence, 1875 July 22-26 (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Red Cloud Correspondence and List of Witnesses, 1875 July 27-31, August (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - Red Cloud Correspondence, 1875 August 1-15 (Box 52, Folder 20)
  - Red Cloud Correspondence, 1875 August 16-31 (Box 52, Folder 21)
  - Red Cloud Correspondence, Marsh's statement and Delano's attack, 1875 September 1-10 (Box 52, Folder 22)
  - Red Cloud correspondence and Alvord statement, 1975 September 11-30 (Box 52, Folder 23)
  - Red Cloud Correspondence, 1875 -1891 (Box 52, Folder 24)
  - Reply to Saville, notes, list of witnesses, 1875 (Box 52, Folder 25)
  - Notes on Red Cloud Hearings, 1875 (Box 52, Folder 26)
  - Pamphlets on Indians, 1868, 1871 (Box 52, Folder 27)
  - Pamphlets on Red Cloud Investigation, 1874 (Box 52, Folder 28)
  - Pamphlets on Red Cloud including Marsh's statement, 1875 (Box 52, Folder 29)
  - Red Cloud, New York Herald-Tribune Book Review. (Missing as of 6-8-1990), 1838 June 26 (Box 52, Folder 30)
  - Red Cloud. House Report on Indian Affairs, 1874 (Box 53, Folder 31)
  - Red Cloud. Report of Special Commission, 1875 (Box 53, Folder 32)
  - Red Cloud. Report of Special Commission. (incomplete), 1875 (Box 53, Folder 33)
  - Red Cloud Controversy. Small Scrapbook, 1875 (Box 54, Folder 34)
  - Red Cloud Controversy. Large Scrapbook (including Marsh's Statement), 1875 (Box 54, Folder 35)
  - House Report on transfer of Indian Bureau to Army, 1876 (Box 54, Folder 36)
- Additional material
  - Cards from original Marsh family papers in Peabody (not filmed), Undated (Box 55)
- Additional material, Circa 1873; Accession 2010-M-050
  The accession comprises stereographs from O.C. Marsh's 1873 expedition to the western United States. The photographs depict primarily conditions in camp, and include one labeled Camp of the Dacotas that appears to have been taken and commercially distributed by W. H. Jacoby.
  - Stereographs, Circa 1873 (Box 1, Folder 1)